### How can we help you?

 _search_

#### [Getting started](#panelBody59)

#### [Create survey _arrow\_right_](#collapse5966)

#### [Distribute survey _arrow\_right_](#collapse5967)

#### [Analyze survey _arrow\_right_](#collapse5968)

#### [Genie _arrow\_right_](#collapse59265)

#### [Survey design and settings](#panelBody60)

#### [Creating surveys _arrow\_right_](#collapse6069)

#### [Question types _arrow\_right_](#collapse6070)

#### [Question settings _arrow\_right_](#collapse6071)

#### [Design & branding _arrow\_right_](#collapse6072)

#### [Survey logic _arrow\_right_](#collapse6073)

#### [Custom variables _arrow\_right_](#collapse6074)

#### [Multilingual surveys _arrow\_right_](#collapse6075)

#### [Survey settings _arrow\_right_](#collapse6076)

#### [Rewards and incentives _arrow\_right_](#collapse6077)

#### [Manage & organize surveys _arrow\_right_](#collapse6078)

#### [Survey security _arrow\_right_](#collapse6079)

#### [Distribution](#panelBody61)

#### [Ways to distribute _arrow\_right_](#collapse6180)

#### [Response tracking _arrow\_right_](#collapse6181)

#### [Mobile and offline app _arrow\_right_](#collapse6182)

#### [Survey audience _arrow\_right_](#collapse6183)

#### [Reports & analytics](#panelBody62)

#### [Analyzing your data _arrow\_right_](#collapse6284)

#### [Text analysis _arrow\_right_](#collapse6285)

#### [Choice modeling _arrow\_right_](#collapse6286)

* [Anchored MaxDiff Analysis \[BETA Release\]](https://www.questionpro.com/help/anchored-maxdiff.html)

#### [Manage & export data _arrow\_right_](#collapse6287)

#### [Integration](#panelBody63)

#### [CRMs _arrow\_right_](#collapse6388)

#### [Marketing _arrow\_right_](#collapse6389)

#### [Analysis tools _arrow\_right_](#collapse6390)

#### [API & Webhooks _arrow\_right_](#collapse6391)

#### [Account & billing](#panelBody64)

#### [Account management _arrow\_right_](#collapse6492)

#### [Billing _arrow\_right_](#collapse6493)

#### [Security & privacy](#panelBody65)

#### [Legal _arrow\_right_](#collapse6594)

#### [Compliance _arrow\_right_](#collapse6595)

#### [Authentication](#panelBody203)

#### [SSO _arrow\_right_](#collapse203204)

#### [XA3](#panelBody221)

#### [Manage Insights _arrow\_right_](#collapse221222)

#### [Getting Started _arrow\_right_](#collapse221229)

×

QuestionPro Privacy Policy
==========================

QuestionPro Privacy Policy Effective Date: December 27th, 2023

General Information

This privacy policy also applies to all sites own and operated by QuestionPro - including but not limited to;

* https://www.questionpro.com
* https://www.questionpro.de
* https://eu.questionpro.com
* https://ca.questionpro.com
* https://ae.questionpro.com
* https://au.questionpro.com
* https://sa.questionpro.com
* https://www.questionpro.io
* https://sa.questionpro.com
* https://www.questionprogov.com
* https://www.surveyanalytics.com

This Privacy Statement describes how QuestionPro collects and uses the personal information you provide. It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information.

QuestionPro strives to conform its privacy practices, policies and/or procedures with any and all applicable international, country-specific, US Federal, state, and/or local laws, codes, regulations, and requirements, and the industry codes, standards, and regulations of various market and opinion research professional associations and/or organizations, including, without limitation, the ICC/ESOMAR International Code on Market and Social Research and the Code of Standards and Ethics for Survey Research of the Council of American Survey Research Organizations (CASRO). QuestionPro is committed to protecting the security and integrity of all personal information collected by or disclosed to QuestionPro. QuestionPro will not use any personal information for direct marketing or advertising purposes, and membership as a panel member and/or participation in any survey(s) are completely voluntary. This privacy policy identifies the personal information that QuestionPro collects; how such personal information will be used and protected; and your rights.

INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE

Registration

In order to use this Web site, you must first complete the registration form and create a username and password. During registration, you are required to give contact information (including email address). We use this information to contact you about the services on our site in which you have expressed interest.

After registering with the site, we use your email address to provide you with a series of “Ongoing Communications and Product Updates” (see "Communication from the Site"). These communications are used to give you a better understanding of the site, what it offers, and how it is best utilized. As always, you have the option not to receive these types of communications (see “Choice and Opt-out” in "Information Sharing and Disclosure").

By creating an account and providing us with your information, you explicitly consent to the collection, storage, and processing of your personal data.

Orders

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name and billing address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). We use this information for billing purposes. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you. We will also use this information to send you ‘Service-related Communications’ (see ‘Communication from the Site’). These include email confirmations of billing transactions, account upgrades, and account cancellations. Please see “Contact Us” below.

Profile

We store information that we collect through user input, cookies, log files, and user surveys to create a “profile” of preferences. This profile information includes each of the following categories:

Registration Information: username, password, first name, last name, email address, phone

Order Information: credit card number, credit card expiration, billing address

Preferences: profile information that categorizes how the software is utilized

Details of the user profile are used to contact the user (see “Communication from the Site”) and provide tailored promotions and marketing offers and to improve the content of the site.

Profile information may be updated at any time by clicking on the “My Account” link while the user is logged into their administrative account.

SURVEYS OR CONTESTS

If you are a member of a QuestionPro research panel, we may from time-to-time provide you with the opportunity to participate in surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and/or username), and demographic information (such as zip code). We use this information gain knowledge about our users and their experience using the site.

FORWARD TO FRIEND/ADD A USER

A respondent may share a survey with other users by providing email addresses after completing the survey. QuestionPro will automatically send a survey link to those addresses and a one-time email that introduces and invites the addressee to the QuestionPro site. We will not share these email addresses with customers or survey administrators and will not send future mailings unless the addressee requests further communication. Any addressee who has been referred to our site or surveys may contact [\[email protected\]](https://www.questionpro.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) (or use the “Contact Us” link on our homepage) and request to be removed from the database. When you add a new user to your account, such as the “Add User” function on your QuestionPro account, we collect that user’s name, email address and other contact information. QuestionPro stores this information for the sole purpose of providing this service to you as our QuestionPro customer. You or the added user may request to delete this submitted information by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.questionpro.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

USES OF INFORMATION

Any information shared with QuestionPro during the creation of a survey is owned solely by the administrator of that survey. By the nature of how our service works, surveys need to be shared via a URL on the Internet. We provide the option to password-protect your surveys if they contain sensitive content. Email addresses uploaded to the system for the purpose of sending survey invitations and email communication are owned solely by the survey administrator. We will never share any information uploaded to the system with any 3rd parties. Data collected through surveys is owned solely by the survey administrator. By default, the data is only accessible by providing a username and password and logging into the site. There is the option to share online reports via a URL from the administrative account. The survey administrator controls this option. We will never use any of the data collected. QuestionPro may collect the Internet protocol address (the IP address) that is publicly available on your computer. The IP address is not collected for the purpose of tracking or monitoring your activity on the Internet. In non-United States jurisdictions, an IP address may be classified as personal information or personal data under applicable laws; therefore, to the extent that QuestionPro collects IP addresses, QuestionPro will collect, use, maintain, secure and/or disclose IP addresses in accordance with applicable Laws.

COMMUNICATIONS FROM THE SITE

Ongoing Communication and Product Updates

We will occasionally send you information on product enhancements, new services, and additional instruction on utilizing our services. These communications are designed to educate our users on the services offered. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see “Choice and Opt-out” in “Information Sharing and Disclosure.” **Service-related Announcements** We will send you strictly service-related announcements when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Service-related emails are also sent confirming billing transactions, account upgrades, and account cancellations. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to cancel your account.

Customer Service

Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password as well an account manager contact information. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. We save all communication (chats, emails, and calls) between QuestionPro representatives and you for record-keeping, training and quality-assurance purposes.

Survey Invitations

If you are a member of a QuestionPro research panel, we may, from time-to-time, send you email invitations to surveys. We may also periodically send you emails regarding research panel information and communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide information you request.

INFORMATION SHARING AND DISCLOSURE

Personally Identifiable Information Sharing with Partners

We do not share any personally identifiable information with any third parties except as indicated below. If a user specifically requests a service from one of our partnering companies, their personally identifying information will be shared. The partnering company may contact them directly regarding their inquiry. Any requests of partnering companies are initiated solely by the user, and it will be clearly indicated that a partnering company offers the requested service. We may use the third party research panel providers to provide survey respondents for clients who request online survey panels. When you request access to such an online survey panel, your contact information will be shared with third-party research panel providers as necessary for them to provide that service. Third-party research panel providers are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We use a third-party service provider to host chat support on our site. When you request live chat support, your contact information will be stored by the service provider as necessary for it to provide its service. The service provider is prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We use outside credit card processing companies to bill you for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes.

In certain situations, QuestionPro may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or similar legal process. If QuestionPro is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding personally identifiable information.

CHOICE/OPT-OUT

If you no longer wish to receive our product updates, you may opt out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each product update email. If you are a member of a QuestionPro research panel, you may opt out of membership in our research panels by following instructions included in each survey invitation.

TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you. QuestionPro and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies or similar technologies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out at any-time.Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

BULLETIN BOARDS/CHAT ROOMS/ FORUM

If you use a bulletin board or chat room or public forum on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit it here can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or public forum, contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.questionpro.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

TESTIMONIALS

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.questionpro.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

IMPORT CONTACTS

You can import contacts from your email account address book to invite them to take part in surveys. We collect the username and password for the email account you provide and will only use such information for the purpose of inviting contacts to take part in surveys.

ACCESS TO PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

Upon request QuestionPro will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may update, delete or cancel your account at any time by logging into the system and clicking on the “My Account” link. Options for updating your profile and account cancellations are available. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

Under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), the survey respondents have a right to access or challenge the processing of their personal data being held and managed by the administrator of the survey. They can exercise these rights by submitting an individual rights request by filling this [form](https://questionpro.com/t/AQkY3Zhhko)

DATA RETENTION

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

Retention is defined as the maintenance of data in a production or live environment which can be accessed by an authorized user in the ordinary course of business. For the avoidance of doubt, Data used in staging, development, and testing or draft versions of the Application shall not be retained beyond their active use period nor copied into production or live environments.

After active use has expired and according to appropriate exceptions, Data shall be destroyed. For the purposes of enforcing retention in accordance with this policy each department is responsible for the Data it creates, uses, stores, processes, and destroys.

QuestionPro Inc shall be responsible for enforcing the retention, archiving, and destruction of Data. The Legal Department may issue a litigation hold request to QuestionPro Security and Compliance which requires that data relating to potential or actual litigation, arbitration, or other claims, demands, disputes, or regulatory action be retained in accordance with instructions from the Legal Department.

Each employee shall be responsible for returning Data in their possession or control to QuestionPro upon separation or retirement. The final disposition of such Data shall be determined by the immediate supervisor in accordance with this policy.

The System will store data from your surveys/campaigns/polls as long as your account is current and active. If data is removed (User deleting surveys, responses, questions, answers, campaigns, polls, etc.) the system will remove the data permanently from the primary database servers immediately. The same data will be present in our backup systems for 7 days, after which it will be removed from all our systems. In some cases, if important items (like surveys etc.) are deleted, they may not be removed from our systems immediately. Data may be placed in a recycle bin and permanently removed after 7 days. We will not accommodate requests for restoring data from our backup systems unless it is a system or hardware failure on our part. No Exceptions.

SECURITY

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information such as credit card number on our order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

LINKS TO 3RD PARTY SITES

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of QuestionPro. If you submit personally identifiable information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

SOCIAL MEDIA WIDGETS

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

SINGLE SIGN-ON

You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

CHANGES IN THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our homepage prior to the change becoming effective.

THIRD-PARTY SERVICES AND DATA HANDLING

To enhance the functionality of QuestionPro, we integrate with trusted third-party services (such as Google, Facebook, etc.) and, in doing so, may require the storage of credentials for these services. These credentials are securely encrypted in our database and are utilized strictly to access the data you authorize. We may log certain non-identifiable information to facilitate support and resolve technical issues.

Additionally, we collaborate with select trusted third parties (e.g., providers of customer support and IT services) to assist in delivering, improving, protecting, and promoting our Services. These third parties are granted access to your information solely to perform tasks on our behalf, in strict accordance with our Privacy Policy. We remain responsible for their handling of your information and ensure they comply with our privacy and security standards.

We are committed to safeguarding your data and do not use information obtained through Google Workspace APIs to develop, improve, or train generalized AI and/or machine learning models.

In certain circumstances, we may disclose your information to third parties if it is determined to be reasonably necessary to: (a) comply with legal obligations; (b) protect individuals from death or serious bodily injury; (c) prevent fraud or abuse of QuestionPro or our users; or (d) protect QuestionPro's property rights.

For more detailed information on our Third-Party Service Integration, please visit [this page](https://questionpro.com/help/integration-privacy-policy.html).

CONTACT US

QuestionPro is committed to working with individuals to obtain a fair resolution to any complaints or disputes about privacy and personal information. QuestionPro commitment to privacy is demonstrated and documented by our internal Privacy Compliance Officer, by our adherence to the applicable laws and codes. If you have any complaints or concerns about this privacy policy you can contact:

Erik Koto
Privacy Compliance Officer
QuestionPro
9450 SW Gemini Dr #62790,
Beaverton, OR 97008-7105, USA
Email: [\[email protected\]](https://www.questionpro.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

United States of America: +1 (800) 531 0228
United Kingdom: +44 20 8080 9780
Australia: +61 2 8074 5080
Fax: +1 (206) 260-3243

For any kind of data erasure requests you can email us at - [\[email protected\]](https://www.questionpro.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).
You can also [cancel](https://www.questionpro.com/help/canceling-account.html) the QuestionPro account by your self.

Was the article helpful?

[Yes](javascript:void(0);) [No](javascript:void(0);)

How can we improve it?

Submit

Thank you for submitting feedback.

Just a moment...

Ask Question

[Login to post _close_](javascript:openHelpWindow('/a/showLogin.do?login=helpLogin');)

You may also be interested in... [Terms of Use](https://www.questionpro.com/help/terms-of-use.html) [Data Security](https://www.questionpro.com/help/security.html) [Accessibility Statement](https://www.questionpro.com/help/accessibility-statement.html) [Browser Requirements](https://www.questionpro.com/help/minimum-system-requirement.html) [Performance Metrics](https://www.questionpro.com/help/performance-metrics.html) [Data Retention Policy](https://www.questionpro.com/help/data-retention-policy.html)

### GET STARTED WITH YOUR FIRST SURVEY NOW

### GET STARTED WITH YOUR FIRST SURVEY NOW

### Still have questions?

### Still have questions?
